<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Nakamoto</title>
    <description>An educational portal for sound money and technology.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 14:15:58 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 14:15:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scaling Money I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This series covers my first draft of the various chapters for my upcoming book. These articles have not been through fact checks or editing and will not be the final version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bartering--the-first-kind-of-money&quot;&gt;Bartering — The first kind of money&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is money, why does it exist and when did it come to be? To start answering these questions, we need to look back to when we lived in small groups, tribes or villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time we see the most basic form of money — Not the kind we see today, or even the types of money we read about in history books, like shells, beads or salt — the first kind of money is simply anything of value, that is exchangeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exchanging forms the foundation of human life, without exchanges, we would have essentially no society. From a young age we start inventing forms of money by placing value on our possessions, and offering them to the markets we have access to. Even before kindergarten, you will likely have experienced some form of exchange, whether it was trading marbles, action figures or collectible cards, within your school an economy around every kids possessions was formed. Some kids participated and some didn’t, but it was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This economy however, is limited, and is dependent on everyone owning something of value to participate. But how is value determined? The value assigned by the owner is not always the value assigned by the market, so when I want to trade my blue marbles for red ones, I might decide that one blue marble is worth two red ones. My classmate however, might view blue and red marbles equally, so he might counter my offer and if we then agree that they are of equal value, we set the price for an exchange of blue and red marbles. In another scenario, my classmate may have too many red marbles, and too few blue ones, making red marbles more valuable than blue ones to me, and blue marbles more valuable to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both examples, the exchange between us is voluntary, and the only reason that the trade happens is because we both expect to benefit from it. We both benefit from it because we both perceive what we give up to be less valuable than what we get back. Since I have an excess of blue marbles, and my classmate an excess of red, we value the marbles we already have lower than the ones we need because our supply exceeds our requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that when an exchange takes place, it’s a record of the value of the items exchanged, but this simply isn’t the case. If I exchange a cup of coffee for a 1 carat diamond, it doesn’t mean that diamonds are worth less after that exchange, nor does it make coffee worth more. All that an exchange measures is the value of the items relative to those making the exchange. (This is something we’ll come back to when we discuss Bitcoin later)
Exchanging goods and services was and is the absolute foundation of society, this is because every person, their circumstances and skills differ. An egg farmer values fish more than eggs since he can obtain eggs with ease, but not fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-limitations-of-barter&quot;&gt;The limitations of barter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the exchange of goods is so fundamentally important to our survival as individuals and as a species, it would be impossible to scale because this type of direct exchange isn’t much more efficient than living off the grid and being able to self-sustain. Take our egg farmer for example; she wants to build a new coop, and in a world without money, she offers to pay with what she has — eggs.
The first problem we face is that not everyone needs or wants eggs, so the people she hires to build her coop may not all accept eggs as payment. The second issue is that the items you exchange are not always easily divisible. While eggs are a reasonably small item and individual eggs are relatively inexpensive, so can be used to buy more expensive items, a shoemaker could hardly separate a pair of shoes to pay for something because a $100 pair of shoes is worth very little to nothing if you only have one of them.
This also doesn’t mean that items that can be easily divisible are easier to transact with, because you then run into the first problem, where you may not be able to exchange what you have for what you need. This creates a scenario where you may have to jump through various sets of goods to buy the item that you actually want. Say our egg farmer wants shoes, but our shoemaker doesn’t want eggs, he wants cheese, and our cheesemaker wants milk, and our dairy farmer wants eggs. The Egg farmer has to sell their eggs for milk, then sell the milk for cheese, and the cheese for shoes, and then she finally gets the shoes she needed. Other than the huge effort that she has to go through to get the shoes, it also costs more to make multiple exchanges due to indivisibility, transport costs, and might even lose a little bit of value each time she makes an exchange on her journey to new shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;primitive-money&quot;&gt;Primitive Money&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the efficiency loving beings that we are, humans figured out how to scale economies by indirect exchange. Indirect exchange is the process of the egg farmer buying and selling into one or more other products in order to buy what she actually needs, based on the needs of the seller of the item she wants to buy.
This is still an inefficient means of exchange, but indirect exchange lead us to discover (or invent — whichever you prefer) the mechanism of a medium of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider again our egg farmer. This time she needs to buy some tools for her farm. The Blacksmith doesn’t need eggs, but he does need salt, so our farmer buys salt and sells the salt for the tools she needs. On the other side of the village, the baker sells his bread for salt because he needs it for making bread, and also uses the salt to buy flour from the mill.
In this scenario salt becomes incredibly marketable because everyone is confident that they will be able to sell salt to get the goods that they need. This in turn makes salt more valuable because it starts being used as a medium of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended for informational purposes only. The views expressed in this post are not, and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendations. This article is not an offer, nor the solicitation of an offer, to buy or sell any of the assets or securities mentioned herein. All opinions in this post are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Scaling-money-I/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Scaling-money-I/</guid>
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sharding II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In our last update, we discussed what sharding is, the problems it aims to solve and some of the hurdles we need to overcome to effectively implement it. Today we’ll look at cross-shard transactions, invalid transactions, and malicious behavior.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic type of shard we described in our last article isn’t a very useful or practical method of sharding, because they can’t communicate with each other, which makes them as useful as one individual blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take the example of making a simple payment. If user A and user B were on the same shard, the validators within the shard would be able to process the transaction without issue, but what happens when they have accounts on different shards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User A is on shard #1 and user B is on shard #2. The validators on the individual shards would not be able to debit or credit the users’ accounts because they would have no authority on each others’ respective shards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are however solutions to this problem, so let’s take a look at some of them in a little more detail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;synchronous-same-time-cross-shard-transactions&quot;&gt;Synchronous (same-time) cross-shard transactions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, when user A on shard #1 needs to send funds to user B on shard #2, the blocks in each shard that contains state transition that’s related to the transaction itself are produced simultaneously, and the validators on each shard work collaboratively to confirm the transaction. Vitalik Buterin proposed merge blocks with this solution back in early 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;asynchronous-cross-shard-transactions&quot;&gt;Asynchronous cross-shard transactions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly easier operation to complete, and far simpler to coordinate so it is more popular than synchronous transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we’ll use the example of user A on shard #1 wanting to send money to user B on shard #2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, the shard in charge of crediting user B’s account will only validate its part of the transaction once it has enough proof that the shard in charge of debiting user A’s account has been done.
This approach is not perfect though, there is a non-zero chance that one of the blocks of one of the shards gets orphaned. A non-zero chance, however unlikely is still a vulnerability that can’t be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the figure below into consideration we’ll look at why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/The-Nakamoto/thenakamoto.com/blob/gh-pages/assets/posts/ShardingII-1.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Asynchronous Cross-Shard Transactions&quot; title=&quot;Asynchronous Cross-Shard Transactions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blockchain has two shards, and by pure coincidence, they both fork at the exact point that the transaction is incorporated into block A in shard #1 and block X’ in shard #2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a fork like this happens, the shard has to orphan one of the chains and accept the other. In this case, if chain A, B, etc. becomes the accepted chain in shard #1 and chain W’, X’, etc. becomes the accepted chain in shard #2, then the transaction gets finalized and everyone is happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the A’, B’ etc. chan in shard #1 is accepted and chain W, X etc. in shard #2 is accepted, then the entire transaction fails, which is also an acceptable outcome, because the transaction can be resent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if chain A, B, etc. is accepted in shard #1 and chain W, X, etc. is accepted in shard #2? One part of the transaction is finalized (A, B, etc.) and the other part of the transaction is abandoned (W, X, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-that-it&quot;&gt;Is that it?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a better understanding of sharding and how it works, you might be satisfied, or have more questions, there is however at least one more thing to consider: bad actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;malicious-nodes&quot;&gt;Malicious nodes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s quite common (in any scenario) that when there is the potential for a large payday, there will be people out there thinking of ways to beat the system, whatever that system might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;approving-invalid-blocks&quot;&gt;Approving invalid blocks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad actor nodes might decide that they want to attack the network by creating blocks that attempt to alter the network. Using user #1 and #2, let’s hypothesize that User #1 has 10 coins and user #2 has 0 tokens. Malicious nodes on the network could attempt to create a block when user #1 sends those 10 coins to user #2, which ends up with user #1 having 0 coins and user #2 has 1000 coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/The-Nakamoto/thenakamoto.com/blob/gh-pages/assets/posts/ShardingII-2.jpeg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Approving invalid blocks&quot; title=&quot;Approving invalid blocks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a regular blockchain that isn’t sharded, this type of attack is impossible, since every node validates every block, and if an invalid block is discovered, all the nodes (whether they are miners or not) reject that block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With classic blockchains, it doesn’t matter how many blocks malicious nodes create, or how fast they create them, the honest actors of the network will always ignore those blocks and continue building the honest chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a chain that splits into two because bad nodes want to build invalid blocks to fill their accounts with a bunch of coins. The malicious nodes might even outnumber the honest nodes as is this case. The shorter chain is the honest chain, and the longer one is invalid. In a regular non-sharded blockchain, every participant is responsible for validating all the blocks they receive and confirming the state, therefore anyone who has a vested interest in the blockchain (and by extension its integrity) would immediately recognize the invalid chain and disregard it for the (in this case) shorter chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/The-Nakamoto/thenakamoto.com/blob/gh-pages/assets/posts/ShardingII-3.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Approving invalid blocks&quot; title=&quot;Approving invalid blocks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sharded chain is a little more complex because participants can’t validate every transaction on each shard, so we have to figure out how to confirm that there are no invalid blocks within the entire history of the shard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the beacon chain (discussed in our last post) doesn’t normally have the capacity to validate every block in every shard, we need another solution to ensure the integrity of each chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that the network, and by association, each shard has a Byzantine Fault Tolerance mechanism, and the malicious nodes within a shard control less than 66.667% you could build a mechanism that alerts the system if there are any attempts to generate invalid blocks, wherein one or more honest nodes could attest to valid or invalid blocks. If more than 66.667% of the shard is controlled by malicious nodes, then they could theoretically finalize blocks, however as long as one node within the shard is honest, a mechanism can be built to allow honest nodes to contest malicious ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended for informational purposes only. The views expressed in this post are not, and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendations. This article is not an offer, nor the solicitation of an offer, to buy or sell any of the assets or securities mentioned herein. All opinions in this post are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Sharding-II/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Sharding-II/</guid>
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sharding I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this two-part explainer, we look at the Ethereum blockchain, sharding, and how sharding will allow blockchains to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is the blockchain most synonymous with the concept of sharding, and to understand why the Ethereum developer community wants to implement sharding, it’s important to understand what it is, and why it’s an attractive solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to ETH Gas Station, it takes around 1.78 minutes for a transaction to be added to the Ethereum blockchain, with new blocks being produced every 32 seconds with an average of 15–20 transactions being processed a second. This ecosystem creates an environment that favors miners over users, where if a user wants to prioritize their transaction, they have to increase their gas prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low throughput in conjunction with high latency and prices limit the network, and as a result, the network is less suitable for services and applications that need to scale as they are adopted. The primary reason for Ethereum’s low throughput is due to the requirement for every node on the network to process every transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-sharding&quot;&gt;What is sharding?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, sharding is a way of partitioning to spread out computational and storage workloads across a P2P network so that each node isn’t responsible for processing the entire network’s transactional load but rather only maintains information related to its partition (or shard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further explain sharding we can use the very simplest example of sharding. Vitalik Buterin, the founder of Ethereum refers to this as “scaling by 1000 altcoins”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this instance, instead of running a single blockchain, we run multiple blockchains and instead of referring to each as a blockchain, we call each chain a shard. Each shard, in turn, has its own network of validators or nodes which either mine blocks using a PoW algorithm, or by staking or voting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-challenges-to-sharding&quot;&gt;The challenges to sharding&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first issue we find when attempting to use sharding is that because each shard has its own set of nodes, each shard is less secure than having a single chain like Ethereum. So if Ethereum with the 𝑥 amount of nodes decided to hard fork and split into a sharded chain, and distributed the network over 10 shards, each shard would have 1% of the original chains’ security. This means that each shard could be compromised or corrupted by controlling 5.1% of the nodes of the original chain as opposed to 51% of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/The-Nakamoto/thenakamoto.com/blob/gh-pages/assets/posts/ShardingI-1.jpeg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;51% Majority&quot; title=&quot;51% Majority&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second problem we run into is: “how do we / who chooses which node validates which shard?” For a bad actor, controlling 5.1% of the network’s nodes is only a problem if they are all validating in the same shard. Allowing nodes to choose which shard they validate within could cause frequent network attacks, so the best way to minimize the risk of attack is to not allow nodes to choose which shard they validate for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/The-Nakamoto/thenakamoto.com/blob/gh-pages/assets/posts/ShardingI-2.jpeg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;51% Majority&quot; title=&quot;51% Majority&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtually all sharding architecture relies on randomness to assign nodes to a shard. Assigning nodes to a shard requires calculations that aren’t shard specific and almost all of these designs make use of a separate chain that handles the maintenance of the entire network of shards and nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chain, referred to as a beacon chain in Ethereum, is responsible for generating random numbers, assigning nodes to shards, taking snapshots of individual shards, processing stakes and various other functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beacon chains have a few of their shortcomings. They are responsible for the record keeping computations mentioned before, so the more shards that a network makes use of, the more work the beacon chain has to do, resulting in the same problem that a network without sharding might encounter — Low throughput in conjunction with high latency, so the scalability of a sharded network has a natural limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sharded network does, however, have multiplicative properties, so if there are improvements to the efficiency of the network that result in the nodes in the network processing transactions four times faster, the beacon chain would be able to handle four times the amount of shards, improving the network speed by 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-data-be-split-into-shards&quot;&gt;How can data be split into shards?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by looking at what functions nodes typically perform on a blockchain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They process/validate transactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They relay these transactions as well as the blocks they mine to other nodes on the network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They store the history of all transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a network grows, nodes need to be able to keep up with the requirements of the network, so as the network grows;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing the number of transactions being processed required each node to add more computing power&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More transactions being relayed requires more bandwidth from the node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storing all the data on the blockchain also gradually requires the node to add more storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these three parameters you’ll notice that data storage will grow whether the number of transactions per second or number of transactions that are relayed increases or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, the sharding of storage but not transactions have been proposed, and some projects have implemented the sharding of transaction processing but not the storage, however, the most common type of sharding being worked on is called “State Sharding” and this consists of the nodes in each shard building their own blockchain that contains transactions that only affect their part of the entire global network, which means that nodes only need to store their shards’ transaction history, process transactions that affect their shard and relay those transactions within their shard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our next part, we’ll look at cross-shard transactions, invalid transactions and malicious behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended for informational purposes only. The views expressed in this post are not, and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendations. This article is not an offer, nor the solicitation of an offer, to buy or sell any of the assets or securities mentioned herein. All opinions in this post are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Sharding-I/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Sharding-I/</guid>
        
        <category>Ethereum</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        
        <category>Ethereum</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are UTXO's?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Scaling is one of the most talked-about things when it comes to blockchain, its the endless battle of trying to balance security, speed, and storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we’ll look at UTXO’s — something you might have heard of before, but didn’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; grasp. Since this is a slightly more complicated topic, I’ll add reminders on what UTXO stands for (unspent transaction output).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A UTXO (unspent transaction output) is the output of a transaction that a user receives and can spend in the future. As the name suggests, it is the &lt;em&gt;unspent&lt;/em&gt; output of a transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a UTXO’s as paper money or coins. If you have thirty-seven dollars in your wallet or purse, you’ll have a combination of paper and coins in your possession that makes up the $37.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UTXO’s in your wallet or purse are the individual notes and coins that you hold. These are little chunks of money that you can use in any combination to make a purchase — just like “ &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; “ money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the same in a Bitcoin wallet. When you open it, you see the $37 balance, and like your coins and papers, this balance could be made up of one or many UTXO’s (unspent transaction outputs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UTXO’s are even more similar to fiat money as we dig deeper. Sometimes you go to the store and want to buy a soda, and you may not have the exact change, maybe the soda costs $1.50, and you only have a $10 bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you purchase the soda is to overpay the teller at the store, and then the teller gives you back the difference (pay $10 and get $8.50 in return). This is the same as spending money with Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network requires you to send at least one full UTXO to complete a transaction — You can’t pay for a $10 purchase by cutting a $20 bill in half, and the same can be said for a UTXO (unspent transaction output).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy something that costs 0.4 bitcoins, and your wallets’ balance consists of two UTXO’s (unspent transaction outputs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first UTXO being 0.15BTC and the second being 0.3 BTC making your total balance 0.45 BTC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you don’t have a single UTXO or a combination that perfectly adds up to 0.4 BTC, you send both UTXO’s out to the network (overpay the teller), the merchant then receives a UTXO of 0.4 BTC, and you are sent back a new UTXO of 0.05 BTC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;but-utxos-arent-exactly-like-cash&quot;&gt;But UTXO’s aren’t EXACTLY like cash&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the most basic of terms a UTXO (unspent transaction output) can be compared to cash, there are a few differences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious initial difference is that with a cash transaction, you don’t pay any fees to a network, but with Bitcoin, you also have to factor in the fees paid to miners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UTXO (unspent transaction output) that you receive if you use the same example as above, would be less than 0.05 BTC because of the network fees you need to pay for your transaction to be added to a block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;New UTXO = (total of original UTXO[s]) — (amount sent to a different address) — (transaction fees)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next way in which UTXO’s are different is that they, unlike fiat coins and bills, can be of any value. Fiat coins and bills’ values are determined by each respective government around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is beneficial for a few reasons, for example, you could have a UTXO whose value equals a $1,000,000 but if you wanted the same in cash, you may have to carry 10,000 x $100 bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-first-hurdle&quot;&gt;The first hurdle&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers are usually pretty good at identifying ways in which to optimise these packages to deliver performant and efficient UTXO’s that keep the data weight of the blockchain manageable — a critical aspect to scaling. More efficient UTXO generation means minimal data weight and optimal speed processing speeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains aren’t always better than cash — when you have cash, you don’t know its entire history, and don’t need to either. Inversely, your Bitcoin wallet needs to know the number and quantity of UTXO’s that are associated with your address(es).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that most blockchains that use UTXO’s (unspent transaction outputs) have the requirement that a UTXO can only be assembled or disassembled into smaller or larger sizes is when you are making a transaction. So if you never send or receive funds, the UTXO’s in your wallet can’t be adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a major drawback for end-users, however, there are circumstances where it may be better to be able to adjust the UTXO size before making a transaction. The first reason that comes to mind is privacy. You might want to minimise the information stored about any addresses associated with you, so receiving a UTXO in “change” after sending money to someone will result in more information about the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;one-of-the-biggest-issues-with-utxos-is-the-space-it-requires&quot;&gt;One of the biggest issues with UTXO’s is the space it requires&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UTXO set is currently close to 4GB on disk, and can often can’t be entirely stored in memory as it’s bound by the block size limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UTXO (unspent transaction output) set can also grow as fast as the blockchain itself. In the case of Bitcoin, even after implementing SegWit, which reduces transaction sizes, there is still a close to 50% growth in the UTXO set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This implies that within the next few years we could see the UTXO set grow to close to 20GB, which may be impractical even if you consider Moore’s law, where computers may gain enough storage to run a full Bitcoin node with the most basic computers of the future but we also need to consider data usage, the push for more mobile blockchain solutions and countries where data or bandwidth are more difficult to come by or prohibitively expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will pose an interesting challenge for Bitcoin and other blockchain developers, one which will certainly push developers to their limits both practically and creatively when working on this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended for informational purposes only. The views expressed in this post are not, and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendations. This article is not an offer, nor the solicitation of an offer, to buy or sell any of the assets or securities mentioned herein. All opinions in this post are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/What-are-UTXOs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/What-are-UTXOs/</guid>
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>UTXO</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>UTXO</category>
        
        <category>Scaling</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chancellor on brink of second bailout for banks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the original article that Satoshi Nakamoto referenced in the Bitcoin genesis block.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alistair Darling has been forced to consider a second bailout for banks as the lending drought worsens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor will decide within weeks whether to pump billions more into the economy as evidence mounts that the £37 billion part-nationalisation last year has failed to keep credit flowing. Options include cash injections, offering banks cheaper state guarantees to raise money privately or buying up “toxic assets”, The Times has learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bank of England revealed yesterday that, despite intense pressure, the banks curbed lending in the final quarter of last year and plan even tighter restrictions in the coming months. Its findings will alarm the Treasury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bank is expected to take yet more aggressive action this week by cutting the base rate from its current level of 2 per cent. Doing so would reduce the cost of borrowing but have little effect on the availability of loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whitehall sources said that ministers planned to “keep the banks on the boil” but accepted that they need more help to restore lending levels. Formally, the Treasury plans to focus on state-backed gurantees to encourage private finance, but a number of interventions are on the table, including further injections of taxpayers’ cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under one option, a “bad bank” would be created to dispose of bad debts. The Treasury would take bad loans off the hands of troubled banks, perhaps swapping them for government bonds. The toxic assets, blamed for poisoning the financial system, would be parked in a state vehicle or “bad bank” that would manage them and attempt to dispose of them while “detoxifying” the main-stream banking system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea would mirror the initial proposal by Henry Paulson, the US Treasury Secretary, to underpin the American banking system by buying up toxic assets. The idea was abandoned, ironically, when Mr Paulson decided to follow Britain’s plan of injecting cash directly into troubled banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Darling, Gordon Brown and Lord Mandelson, the Business Secretary, are expected to take the final decision on what extra help to give the banks by the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The banks have taken much of the heat for the economy’s woes. But ministers are said increasingly to accept that attacking the banks will not by itself transform a situation that is jeopardising Britain’s economic prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insiders point out that Mr Darling’s criticism of mortgage lenders has softened in recent weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Bank of England’s radical cuts in interest rates over the past two months, the focus at the Treasury has shifted away from mortgage lending to the pressure being put on businesses by the scarcity of loans, which is emerging as the bigger economic danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Lambert, the Director-General of the CBI, said yesterday: “The Government is going to have to do more to restore credit flows across the economy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that the car industry was especially vulnerable: “Without access to credit or loan guarantees on commercial terms, this vital part of the economy will incur lasting damage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scale of the lending drought was highlighted as separate Bank figures showed that the number of new home loans approved plunged to a record low in November. Only 27,000 mortgages for house purchase were approved by banks and building societies, down from a revised 31,000 in October. It is the lowest level since the Bank began collecting data in 1999. The Bank’s quarterly credit conditions survey showed that banks restricted access to loans of all kinds by companies and consumers in the past quarter, and that they plan to tighten the screws more in this quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halifax reported that the price of the average house fell by more than £100 a day last year. Its quarterly figures showed that the average house ended the year down in price by £37,178, or 16.2 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is intended for informational purposes only. The views expressed in this post are not, and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendations. This article is not an offer, nor the solicitation of an offer, to buy or sell any of the assets or securities mentioned herein. All opinions in this post are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Chancellor-on-brink-of-second-bailout-for-banks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Chancellor-on-brink-of-second-bailout-for-banks/</guid>
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
        
        <category>Bitcoin</category>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrency</category>
        
        <category>Money</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        <category>Fiat</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
